Guide to the John Rutherfurd Papers 1726-1835 (bulk 1775-1835) MS 533
New-York Historical Society
- Series III: Other Persons
  - Subseries 4: Other Persons - General John Reid N.D., 1775 - 1793
    This subseries consists of material related to General John Reid. Business papers include accounts and receipts, primarily for rents paid to Reid by his tenants. Legal papers include deeds, bonds, and agreements. Court papers consist of a [state of case] from a lawsuit by Reid against Capt. James Gray in 1771, and a [state of case] from an unidentified 1785 case, which may have involved property forfeiture. Memoranda are mostly in the handwriting of John Rutherfurd, and refer to Reid's business affairs, including landholdings, rents paid, and interest on bonds.
    - Other Persons -- Gen. John Reid -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, N.D.; 1775-1793 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Other Persons -- Gen. John Reid -- Legal Papers, 1763 - 1787 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Other Persons -- Gen. John Reid -- Court Papers, 1771 - 1785 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Other Persons -- Gen. John Reid -- Memoranda, 1764, 1773, 1784 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 5: Other Persons - Correspondence 1738; 1769-1824; 1835
    This subseries includes correspondence to and from persons other than John and Walter Rutherfurd, or specific persons in the Other Persons series. Correspondents include Richard Duncan and John Duncan, who wrote to Peter Van Brugh Livingston about business matters. James Longstreet wrote, perhaps to a newspaper, regarding to the Delaware River Bridge. Dirck ten Broeck wrote to Philip Livingston about business matters that may have also involved the Rutherfurds. J. Alsop of the Corporation for the Relief of Widows & Children of Clergymen of the Episcopal Church corresponded with Jacob LeRoy and John Wilcocks concerning that organization's charitable activities.
    - Other Persons -- Correspondence, 1738; 1769-1824; 1835 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 6: Other Persons - Accounts, Bills, Receipts N.D., 1747 - 1826
    Business and personal material of various persons, including John Duncan.
    - Other Persons -- Accounts, Bills Receipts, N.D., 1747 - 1826 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 7: Other Persons - Court Papers N.D., 1726, 1748
    This subseries includes the following material: a list of papers relating to the case of William Smith vs. William Alexander (N.D.), a narrative in case for the suit of [James] Alexander vs. Daniel Miller (1726), a list of papers relating to the suit, and an indenture, probably entered as evidence in the suit of [ ] Livingston vs. [ ] Fresneau (1748). The subseries also includes material from cases that cannot be identified. These are: a 1785 deposition of Peter Van Brugh Livingston regarding John Duncan's debt, and, in 1806, depositions of two witnesses attesting to the identity of Robert Walter Rutherfurd.
    - Other Persons -- Court Papers, N.D., 1726, 1748 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Other Persons -- Court Papers -- Unidentified Proceedings, 1785, 1806 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 8: Other Persons - Surveys, Field Notes N.D., 1787, 1800
    Subseries includes field notes for surveys and surveys of tracts in various counties of New Jersey.
    - Other Persons -- Surveys, Field Notes, N.D., 1787, 1800 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Series IV: Corporation for the Relief of Widows and Children of Clergymen 1785 - 1809
  This series includes minutes, reports, legal papers and memoranda of the corporation.
  - Corporation for the Relief of Widows and Children of Clergymen -- Minutes and Reports, 1785 - 1809 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Corporation for the Relief of Widows and Children of Clergymen -- Legal Papers, 1801 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Corporation for the Relief of Widows and Children of Clergymen -- Memoranda, 1793 - 1809 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Series V: Society for Establishing Useful Manufactures 1816
  This series includes legislation and an indenture regarding a transfer stock in the society, and reports and accounts regarding the society's real estate.
  - Society for Establishing Useful Manufactures -- Legislation and Indenture re Stock Transfer, 1816 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Society for Establishing Useful Manufactures -- Report on Real Estate; Real Estate Accounts, [1816] (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Series VI: Abstracts of Legislation re New Jersey -- New York Boundary 17??
  - Abstracts of Legislation re New Jersey -- New York Boundary, 17? (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Series VII: [Map of Turnpike Route] N.D.
  What appears to be a map of a proposed or actual turnpike route through New Jersey.
  - [Map of Turnpike Route], N.D. (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Series VIII: Fragments [N.D.]
  - Fragments, N.D. (Box 5, Folder 23)